Guide to the Silver Connections Collection RG.066
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
Silver Connections Collection
1990-2018
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
RG.066
1 Linear Feet
This collection contains 5 Silver Connections monographs by Philip Ashforth Coppola: Volume I (books 1 and 2), Volume III, and Volume IV. The collection also contains correspondence from Coppola to Poly/Tandon Prof. Bruce Garetz, an index to Silver Connections Volume I, and a copy of "One Track Mind," edited by Ezra Bookstein and Jeremy Workman with illustrations by Coppola (Princeton Architectural Press).
Books were sent to NYU Conservation and received supportive treatment on the bindings in summer 2025.
Content Description
This collection contains 5 Silver Connections monographs by Philip Ashforth Coppola: Volume I (books 1 and 2), Volume III, and Volume IV. The collection also contains correspondence from Coppola to Poly/Tandon Prof. Bruce Garetz, an index to Silver Connections Volume I, and a copy of "One Track Mind," edited by Ezra Bookstein and Jeremy Workman with illustrations by Coppola (Princeton Architectural Press).
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Tandon professor Bruce Garetz in 2025. The accession number associated with this gift is 2025-004.
Arrangement
This collection has been organized into two series: Series 1. Silver Connections Monographs; Series 2. Correspondance.
Biographical / Historical
Philip Ashforth Coppola is an artist and writer living in New Jersey. His artwork has been featured in The New York Times, Hyperallergic, and other print media. Coppola's work is also part of the permanent collection of the National Arts Club, The Museum of Modern Art, and the S.I.B branch of the New York Public Library.
Coppola began his research for Silver Connections in 1978. Originally intended to be an article about the New York subway stations, Coppola transformed Silver Connections into a multi-volume set with a limited print run. Print run by volume varies, but no volume has more than 300 copies.
Sources:
Project, SoHo Memory. "Silver Connections Books." Philip Ashforth Coppola.
- Series 1: Silver Connections Monographs
  - Silver Connections Volume I, Book I (Revised), 2013; This privately printed edition is first and only; self-published; in sets 0-59. This is copy number 26. Inscribed to Bruce Garetz from the author. (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Silver Connections Volume I, Book II (Revised), 2013; This privately printed edition is first and only; self-published; in sets 0-59. This is copy number 26. (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Silver Connections Volume II, 1990; Limited Edition of 255: This copy is number 243. Title page signed by the author. (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Silver Connections Volume III, 1994; Limited edition of 255, copy number 162. Title page signed by author. (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Silver Connections Volume IV, 1999; Limited edition of 300. This copy is 118. Title page signed by author. (Box 2, Item 2)
  - One Track Mind: Drawing the New York Subway, 2018 (Box 2, Item 3)
  - Index to Silver Connections, Volume I (Revised), 2013 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Correspondance
  - Correspondance: Garetz and Coppola, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 2)